# **Phalgun Guduthur**

Bangalore, India 919900410960 me@phalgun.in http://phalgun.in

I am a backend dev+ops guy with fiddling expertise in HTML & non fancy CSS. In my growing years as a programmer, I have worked on web backend services, location based services on mobile devices and system app development.

I like solving my own problems and feel a tinge of satisfaction if others are helped by it too. I prefer working on something that I can connect with and can take pride in building it. I have contributed to open source projects, started an open source community in my college and am a regular at hackathons in the city.

### **Technical Skills**

Like:

python, java, html, javascript, mysql, rest, git, geolocation

## **Experience**

#### Backend Developer-SignEasy

February 2014 - Current

python, flask, git, amazon-web-services, amazon-s3, nginx, jenkins

- Own the REST API and backend infrastructure of SignEasy.
- Developed a completely new backend API for SignEasy from scratch.
- Completely revamped the file storage infrastructure, twice, to a more reliable and error free system.
- Made the backend more fault tolerant. Brought down the system downtimes to zero.
- Restructured the deployment processes followed by incorporating git and Jenkins
- Maintain the older cloud powered backend of SignEasy APIs and services.
- · Responsible for ops and sanity of the backend.
- · Scripts for product analytics for internal use.

#### System Software Engineer - Akamai Technologies

July 2012 – January 2014

java, rest, javascript, html, jersey, hibernate, python, junit, mockito, elasticsearch, logstash, agile-project-management

- I developed REST API's for Akamai's online store to purchase products. I designed the application interactions with SalesForce and managed it.
- I also wore a dev ops hat I helped develop and maintain a log analysis tool similar to Splunk, which is used to analyze the petabytes of logs Akamai's servers produce.
- Using ElasticSearch and Logstash, designed a log querying tool handling up to 200 GB of data every hour.

### Google Summer of Code - Student Developer-KDE

May 2012 – August 2012

c++, kde, qt, semantic, oop

- Developed a semantic backend plugin for a music player called Amarok to store metadata using Nepomuk framework – Soprano, Strigi and SPARQL. I currently maintain the new backend for Amarok.
- I made sure that the code I wrote was pushed upstream and it went public with Amarok version 2.7

Intern - Framework Engineer – MobStac - Mobile Motion Technologies python, bash, xpath, rss, lxml, pyunit

June 2011 – July 2011

- Wrote a web page crawler that extracted various social media widgets using lxml
- · Support for vimeo and flickr rss parsing
- Played around briefly with mongodb for analytics

# **Education**

#### B.E. Computer Science - PES Institute of Technology (Autonomous)

2008 - 2012

- CGPA of 8.46 on a relative grading scheme.
- Distinction awardee for all 8 semesters
- Was the event head of the first 24 hour hackathon in PESIT Ayana (http://ayana.pes.edu/)
- Co-founded *PES Open Source Community*( http://pesos.pes.edu) to evangelize open source development and contribution which is still going strong.
- Co-founded Student Nokia Developer to help form a community of students developing mobile applications.

#### Social Psychology - Coursera

2013 - 2013

Psychology is a hobby, I'm keen on understanding human behavior and what influences them. I completed the course with a *Statement of Accomplishment* 

(https://www.dropbox.com/s/20u16p5kzs4k6c6/Coursera%20socialpsychology%202013.pdf).

# **Projects & Interests**

**GitHub - amarok-nepomuk** – https://github.com/phalgun/amarok-nepomuk c++, qt, kde

July 2012 - November 2012

This is my GSoC 2012 project for KDE and the awesome Amarok community.

Developed the whole project and was mentored by the Amarok community.

# **GitHub - Pricekart**—https://github.com/phalgun/Pricekart javascript, google-chrome-extension

August 2012

Chrome extension which helps you shop easily on e-commerce sites. People usually spend most of their online shopping time comparing prices and delivery times. What if all these were available in one single click? This chrome extension determines the product you are viewing and shows the prices of the product from other e-commerce sites. And you can easily choose the one of your liking without much hassle.

# **GitHub - RepontiK**-https://github.com/phalgun/RepontiK c++, qt, kde

March 2012

A nepomuk based browser to view and search your files, music, images, contacts and email.

**AutoMeter** – http://www.getjar.mobi/mobile/49736/AutoMeter java-me, jsr179

Beat AutoRickshaws with fake meters. This application tells what the exact fare is and helps you in case of a tampered meter. No need of GPRS and the application is free to use. Customized for Bangalore but can be used anywhere.

Developed the whole application in under 2 hours. More than 40k downloads till date.